viewsonic.com 2019-12-20

# Privacy Policy

## PRIVACY POLICY & COOKIES

Last updated: October 1, 2018

ViewSonic is committed to protecting your privacy and treats the handling of personal data seriously. The Privacy Policy below details how ViewSonic will treat your personal data after it has been collected by ViewSonic through your use of the Website. ViewSonic maintains the privacy of your information using security technologies and adhere to policies that prevent unauthorized use of your personal information. By using this Website, you consent to the collection and use of your information.

Websites you link to from ViewSonic.com may have their own privacy policy that may differ from ViewSonic’s. Please review those websites’ privacy policies for detailed information on how they may use information gathered while you are visiting them.

Please click the following links to learn more about our Privacy Policy:

  1. What information does ViewSonic.com collect and how is it used?
  2. How does ViewSonic.com share personal information?
  3. How does ViewSonic.com respond to ‘Do Not Track’ Signals?
  4. Cookie Policy
  5. California Privacy Rights
  6. International Users
  7. Children’s Privacy
  8. Policy Changes
  9. Contact Us
  10. Appendix One: Privacy Rights of Individuals Residing in the EU

 **1\. What information does ViewSonic.com collect and how is it used?**

ViewSonic obtains the following categories of personal data:

  * Usernames, mailing address, telephone number, email address, contact information, mac address, IP address, preference, bank or credit card, hardware specification, Windows version, analytic files, log files, and other information you may provide to us in calls, emails, meetings, texts, and events.

 **Information You Give Us.** ViewSonic obtains personal data from you in order to process any requests you may make:

  * When you search for or request details on services or products from the Website, for example, registering a ViewSonic product online or entering a competition.
  * When creating an account or signing up via our website, in person or via an affiliated partner.

The specific types of information collected will depend upon the services you use or subscribe to. For example, when you shop through our web store, we may collect data such as the purchases you have made, items in your shopping cart, and how often you make purchases. To process your order, we may collect your full name, email address, phone number, product serial number, home address, mobile phone number, credit card information, and shipping address.

If you choose not to provide this information, we may not be able to provide the corresponding ViewSonic products and services or respond to your inquiries. By disclosing your personal information via the Website, over the telephone or via email or post you consent to the collection, storage and processing of your personal information by ViewSonic in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use Policy.

ViewSonic might request additional information from you in other areas or in the future. You may choose not to provide this information. ViewSonic might also ask for information about your interests, or for feedback about the Website so that we can improve the Website and/or its service. Providing ViewSonic with this information is always optional.

 **Information We Automatically Collect.** In addition to the information ViewSonic collects directly from you, we also monitor and track usage of our website, viewing and traffic patterns, customer behavior, and other similar information. This information is compiled into a statistical aggregate. This aggregate information is also used, in conjunction with your personal information, for ViewSonic’s internal business and administrative purposes including improvements to the Website, ViewSonic’s product and service offerings, our operations, or our customer service. This information may be obtained from the following sources:

  * Via unconditional data capture measures such as the use of cookies and studying the pages you read frequently (please see our Cookie Policy below).
  * Via your individual IP location. This is a necessary function of the Website that enables ViewSonic to return details of information you have searched for, and in order for ViewSonic to diagnose problems with its server and to administer the website.
  * ViewSonic uses a third party tool, Google Analytics, to analyze traffic on the Website. Google Analytics does not create individual profiles for visitors. Unlike some tracking services, Google Analytics does not have a database of individual profiles for each visitor. Google Analytics only collects aggregate data.
  * During the time you are registered as active with ViewSonic, we will log and record on our secure database calls, emails, meetings, texts, events and any other relevant information.

 **Information Provided by Third Parties.** We also obtain data from publicly available sources, service providers, governing bodies and referees. ViewSonic may combine information collected from these sources with information already in its possession. In addition to the information provided we collect & check data from third parties such as Companies House and accredited bodies.

 **2\. How does ViewSonic.com share personal information?**

Unless otherwise provided in the Privacy Policy or the Terms of Use, ViewSonic will not sell, rent or trade your personal information to third parties for marketing purposes without your express consent. ViewSonic will only pass your data to other third parties in accordance with this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Use, or if required to do so by law. ViewSonic may disclose your data to certain permitted third parties, such as members of the ViewSonic group, ViewSonic’s own professional advisers who are bound by confidentiality codes, and when ViewSonic is legally obliged to disclose your data.

From time to time, ViewSonic may sell a business or a part of a business to another person or company. Such a transfer of ownership could include the transfer of your personal data directly related to that business to the purchasing person or company.

Any non-personally identifiable communication or material you transmit to ViewSonic over this website, by electronic mail or otherwise, including any data, questions, comments, or suggestions will be treated as, non-confidential and non-proprietary. ViewSonic may use anything you transmit or post to its affiliates for any purpose, including but not limited to reproduction, disclosure, transmission, publication, broadcast and posting. Furthermore, ViewSonic is free to use any ideas, concepts, know-how, or techniques contained in any communication you send to this website for any purpose whatsoever, including but not limited to developing manufacturing and marketing products using such information.

 **3\. How does ViewSonic.com respond to ‘Do Not Track Signals’?**

Do Not Track (“DNT”) is a privacy preference that users can set in certain web browsers. DNT is a way for users to inform websites and services that they do not want certain information about their webpage visits collected over time and across websites or online services. We do not recognize or respond to browser-initiated DNT signals, as the Internet industry is currently still working toward defining exactly what DNT means, what it means to comply with DNT, and a common approach to responding to DNT.

 **4\. Cookie Policy**

The ViewSonic ("ViewSonic") website uses cookies. Cookies are small data files which the Site places on your computer or mobile device. This is normal practice for websites. Cookies are essential to help us provide a high-quality website. By collecting information through cookies and other automated means on our Site, we learn how to best tailor the Site to our visitors.

Using these cookies helps us deliver the best web experience for you, and to understand what our readers are looking at so that we can produce more of the right kind of content. We do not use cookies to track your internet browsing activities before or after you visit the Site.

By browsing and using our website, you consent to the above cookies being used in the way described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent, you can disable cookies by adjusting your browser settings or stop using the site. You can also choose to set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the choice of deciding whether to accept it.

The table below explains the cookies we use and why. ****

Cookie|  Name| Purpose| More Information  
---|---|---|---  
ViewSonic| LOOPFUSE, Persistent_id_Qp3J9cqTnEJvDH, Session_Qp3J9cqTnEJvDH, _bizo_bzid,_bizo_cksm, eIFCNu6| ViewSonic uses this cookie to identify your browser and process online transactions. Session cookies help us confirm your identity and are a requirement when using this service. LoopFuse customers are persistent cookies that only ViewSonic can read and use which make it easier for you to log into the Service. Disabling the browser's ability to accept cookies will be able to brows our Site, but will be denied access to the service.| View [Loopfuse Policy](http://www.loopfuse.com/privacy.php)  
Google Analytics| __utma, __utmb ,__utmc, __utmz| These cookies are used to collect infomation about how visitors use our site. We use the information to complie reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of pages visitors to the site, what led customers to the site and the pages that they visited.| View [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)  
Pardot| visitor_id, pi_opt_in, pardot| Pardot tracks visitor and prospect activities on your website and on Pardot landing pages by setting cookies on their browsers. These cookies are set in order to remember preferences when an individual returns to your site, such as form field values. We also set a cookie for Pardot users that are logged into our app, which allows us to maintain the login session, remember table filters, etc.| View [Pardot Privacy policy](http://www.pardot.com/company/legal/privacy-policy/)  
Quantcast.com| __qca| Quantcast.com uses cookies to save your registration ID and login password for future logins to the Quantcast.com site. We also utilize session ID cookies to understand how you interact with the Quantcast.com site and also to monitor aggregate usage by Quantcast Users and web traffic routing on the Quantcast.com site. We also use cookies when you visit websites with tagged content by Quantcast Clients with Quantcast Tags in order to collect Log Data. You may choose to allow your computer to accept cookies, however by diabling cookies, you may not be able to use all portions of the Quantcast.com site or all functionality of the services. Some websites host prior versions of our code that used Flash cookies. We no longer use these cookies for any purpose. In order to delete Flash cookies, please access your Flash Player settings management tool available on Adobe's web site.| View [Quantcast Privacy policy](http://www.quantcast.com/privacy)  
Rubiconproject.com| ruid, rsid, rdk, rdk2, ses, pux, pur_1430, rpb, put_2245, put_2236, put_2181, put_1986, put_1512, put_1185, put_1523, put_2271, put_2100, put_2081, put_2249, put_2025, put_2395| | View [Rubicon Poject Privacy Policy](http://www.rubiconproject.com/privacy-policy/)  
.w55c.net| wfivefivec, matchgoogle| |   
.exelator.com| xud, xudx, ud| | View [Texas Instruments Privacy Policy](http://www.ti.com/corp/docs/legal/privacy.shtml)  
.dlp.com| s_cc, SC_LINKS, s_sq| We use cookie technology to authenticate your access to various areas of our website, tailor its content to your preferences or geographic region, to help us analyze web traffic in general and to track when site visitors complete surveys, so that we do not present a survey again for 90 days. Cookies may be used in interactions where you request something from TI: literature, CD-ROMs, technical support, seminar registrations, personalized web pages, or when you participate in a survey.| View [Exelate Privacy Policy](http://exelate.com/consumer-opt-out/website-privacy-policy/)  
.nohold.net| ASP.NET_SessionId, k18routename5, k18rid5, BIGipServerPOOL-50.56.41.44-80| |   
.turn.com| uid, rrs, rds, rv| | View [Turn Privacy Policy](http://www.turn.com/privacy#two)  
.shop.viewsonic.com| frontend| |   
  
 **5\. California Privacy Rights**

If you are a California consumer, you have the following rights:

  * The right to know what personal information is being collected about you.
  * The right to know whether your personal information is sold or disclosed and to whom.
  * The right to say no to the sale of personal information.
  * The right to access your personal information.
  * The right, in certain circumstances, to delete the information you have provided to us.
  * The right to equal service and price, even if you exercise your privacy rights.

 **Request for Information.** California consumers have the right to request, up to twice in a 12-month period that a business that collects personal information about the consumer disclose to the consumer the information listed below for the preceding 12 months. ViewSonic has the right to request verification of your identity for all requests for information.

(1) The categories of personal information it has collected about that consumer.

(2) The categories of sources from which the personal information is collected.

(3) The business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling personal information.

(4) The categories of third parties with whom the business shares personal information.

(5) The categories of personal information that the business sold about the consumer and the categories of third parties to whom the personal information was sold, by category or categories of personal information for each third party to whom the personal information was sold.

(6) The categories of personal information that the business disclosed about the consumer for a business purpose.

(7) The specific pieces of personal information it has collected about that consumer.

To make such a request, please call us at the following toll-free number 800-688-6688 or visit this webpage <https://www.viewsonic.com/support/customer-service/customer-service-form>.

 **Do Not Sell My Personal Information.** California consumers have the right to opt out of the sale of the consumer’s personal information. To make such a request, please call us at the following toll-free number 800-688-6688 or visit this webpage <https://www.viewsonic.com/support/customer-service/customer-service-form>.

 **Third Party Marketing.** California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [customerservice@viewsonic.com](mailto:customerservice@viewsonic.com). Alternatively, send written correspondence to 10 Pointe Drive, Brea, CA 92821. _[  
](https://www.viewsonic.com/support/customer-service/customer-service-form)_

 **6\. International Users**

Any data that you provide to us may be accessed, shared or processed by our offices, located in the United States, and service providers located in the United States and abroad, if such data transfer is necessary for the specific purpose for which you submitted your data (such as the provision of goods or services under a written contract). This may entail a transfer of your personal information across international borders, including, but not limited to, transfers from within the European Economic Area (the “EEA”) to the United States. The data protections standards may differ and be lower than the standards enforced in your jurisdiction. We maintain appropriate safeguards as required by applicable law for any personal information transferred internationally, and as required by applicable law, will seek your consent prior to such transfers.

 **7\. Children’s Privacy**

ViewSonic.com is not directed at children or minors (as defined by local requirements). We do not knowingly collect personal information from children or minors. If you become aware that a child or minor has provided us with personal information, please contact us at [customerservice@viewsonic.com](mailto:customerservice@viewsonic.com). If we become aware that a child or minor has provided us with personal information, we will take steps to delete such information.

 **8\. Policy Changes**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post these changes on our website so that you will always know what information we gather, how we use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. The privacy practices of sites that may be linked to ViewSonic’s web site are solely the responsibility of that provider and ViewSonic makes no representations nor bears any responsibility regarding the privacy policies of others.

 **9\. Contact Us**

If you have any questions or concerns about the information ViewSonic holds about you may write to ViewSonic at ViewSonic Corporation, 10 Pointe Drive, Brea, California, 92821-7620, or at the following toll-free number 800-688-6688 or visit this webpage <https://www.viewsonic.com/support/customer-service/customer-service-form>.

 **Appendix One: Privacy Rights of Individuals Residing in the EEA.**

If you are an individual residing in the EEA, your privacy rights may be subject to the following terms under the General Data Protection Regulation (EU as amended or updated from time to time shall come into force (the “GDPR”) as stated in Appendix One as follows:

 **Privacy statement**

At ViewSonic or any associated trading names ("ViewSonic") we take protecting the confidentiality of our partners and customers seriously, and with this in mind we adhere to the following Privacy Statement: English law and jurisdiction applies with respect to the content of this site and the information submitted. In particular, we recognize and address our obligations under the provisions of the Data Protection Act (1998) and the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulations).

Under GDPR we must provide information and statements in a clear, concise, transparent, intelligible and easily accessible format.  This policy seeks to do just that when explaining how we collect and manage your data. 

 **How we collect your personal data**

We never knowingly collect more personal data than is strictly necessary to perform our services. ** **

Personal data includes but is not exhausted to user’s name, mailing address, telephone number, email address, contact information, mac address, IP address, preference, bank card, hardware specification, and Windows version. If you choose not to provide this information, we may not be able to provide the corresponding ViewSonic products and services or respond to your enquiries. 

Personal data is collected voluntarily provided to us by customers when creating an account or signing up via our website, in person or via an affiliated partner. By providing your information requested, you enable ViewSonic to provide you with the services you select.

During the time you are registered as active with ViewSonic, we will log and record on our secure database calls, emails, meetings, texts, events and any other relevant information. 

We also obtain data from publicly available sources, service providers, governing bodies and referees. ViewSonic may combine information collected from these sources with information already in its possession. 

In addition to the information provided we collect & check data from third parties such as Companies House and accredited bodies. 

 **How we use your personal data**

ViewSonic will process your personal information for certain legitimate business purposes. Legitimate Interest means the interest of our company in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/products and the best and most secure experience. 

Your information will be collated onto our databases; all relevant paper documents are securely stored on each site. The database is interrogated by our support teams to provide good services. We generally process your personal data only for those purposes that we have communicated with you. 

We will retain your personal data for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is permitted by law or required to fulfil other necessary purposes. For example, to comply with tax law or other laws and regulations, we may retain your personal data within the period requested by such laws and regulations; to follow requests from governments or judiciary for purposes such as investigation or lawsuit, we may retain your personal data for a longer retention period. ** **

 **How we protect your personal data?**

Your personal data security is our highest priority. We have taken steps to protect your personal data by limiting the access to our network where your data is stored. It is our policy to maintain the integrity of any personal data in our possession. Our team only access data that is required to complete their job role. 

Although we do our best to protect the information you share via the internet, anything you submit via the internet is done so at your own risk.

 **Your Rights to your personal data we hold on you:**

  1. Request access to your personal data and obtain a copy
  2. Request data corrections of any incorrect or incomplete data
  3. Request to be removed from our databases and systems
  4. Request to remove consent of data processing
  5. Opt-out or unsubscribe from all non-essential emails by using the unsubscribe option at the foot of all our commercial communications ** **

 **How we use Cookies**

The ViewSonic ("ViewSonic") website uses cookies. Cookies are small data files which the Site places on your computer or mobile device. This is normal practice for websites. Cookies are essential to help us provide a high-quality website. By collecting information through cookies and other automated means on our Site, we learn how to best tailor the Site to our visitors.

Using these cookies helps us deliver the best web experience for you, and to understand what our readers are looking at so that we can produce more of the right kind of content. Our use is subject to Google’s current cookie policy, which you can find here <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>. We do not use cookies to track your internet browsing activities before or after you visit the Site.

By browsing and using our website, you consent to the above cookies being used in the way described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent, you can disable cookies by adjusting your browser settings or stop using the site. ** **

 **Data Sharing & Disclosure**

Except as set out herein and where required or permitted by law or a court of competent jurisdiction, we will not reveal any personal data about you to any third party. ** **

Information will be shared internally within the ViewSonic team to provide business operations. We will only share with third parties when required as part of our services. 

You understand and consent that when you agree to provide your personal data to ViewSonic your personal data may be transferred, stored, used or processed by ViewSonic and any of its affiliated entities or service providers who may be located in a different country to you. All said transfer, storage, or process of your personal data, shall be subject to the Privacy Policy and applicable laws on privacy protection and personal data security. 

From time to time, ViewSonic may sell a business or a part of a business to another person or company. Such a transfer of ownership could include the transfer of your personal data directly related to that business to the purchasing person or company. 

 **Data processing of children or minors**

ViewSonic will NOT knowingly collect personal data from children or minors (as defined by local requirements), and if we learn that we have personal data about a child or minor, we will delete it from our systems. If you are a child or a minor, you must request a parent or guardian to register for the service on your behalf.

 **How to contact us**

If you have any questions, queries or concerns regarding this policy, please contact our Data Protection Officer. 

Company: ViewSonic Corporation

Address: 10 Pointe Dr., Suite 200, Brea, CA 92821, USA

Email: customerservice@viewsonic.com

 **Policy Updates**

As and when required, we may update this policy. If significant changes are made we will notify all ViewSonic services users. By using our services, you consent to this policy.  ** **
